Staci Hartwell (she/her): Is it recording now? Yeah, it is now. Let me click OK.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Okay.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Again, my name is Stacy Hartwell. I'm the Strategic Advisor for the South County Environmental Justice Coalition, and I was also a member of the Qualified Data Center Task Force for Prince George's County, Maryland. I have been the NAACP Maryland State Conference Environmental and Climate Justice Chair for, from, 2018 to 2020.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): 4… And, since then, I've been with the South County Environmental Justice Coalition.
Devin E: Nice, thank you. So, I was… who knows, researching on the… port for the… courtside… Data center.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Task Force?
Devin E: Yes, when I was reaching for it, I just wanted to understand, well, first, could I ask, like, what was your specific role? What did you do on that task force?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Well, I was there as a community representative.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): there were others on… there were… there were two other groups that really represented community on the task force, but the overall number of people who were there were people who benefited from the advance of task force. There seems to be this… this myth
Staci Hartwell (she/her): That, you know, lobbyists have driven into the heads of our legislators and our appointeds that data centers will generate, you know, so much money for the county. But what that money is, it's upfront money that is stolen from the people over time.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): It's like robbing Peter to pay Paul, because they get this lump sum money up front, but they don't think about the long-term costs over the life of the data center to the community. Because we give up, we pay for these data centers in our utility bills.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): In our housing values, with our health, the cost of the environment for water and air and light pollution.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And they don't consider those impacts over time. All they see are the dollars that flash, you know, the smoke and mirrors of dollars flashing in their eyes up front, but not the impacts to their constituents.
Devin E: Yes, I've definitely been reading into that, like.
Devin E: Because I've seen other studies that
Devin E: like, they compared other states, like, the money from data centers, they're… it's not… the revenue's not really coming back the way they promote, so… and this could be a problem in PG County, but I'm also…
Devin E: want to hear your perspective on even just proposal data centers, because, you know, PG County and pairing is in some deficit, and they're trying to find ways to get income. What is your insight and take on that?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): You know, there's something that's called smart money.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And unfortunately, data centers are not smart money. There are smarter ways that we can generate income for the county that don't involve all the harms that come along with data centers.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): So there are less impactful… tourism, and people are like, tourism… yeah, because tourism requires you to have some critical thinking about how you want to position the county, and what you want to put forth is something important. National Harbor is one of the greatest, revenue generators for the county.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): The proposed sphere that they're gonna do, the mini-sphere.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): That would generate more money than a data center, and that's good money, smart money.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): So, there are other things that they can do.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): over, just having a data center. A data center is for the uninspired. It's for the lazy. It's for the people who really don't want to do the work that would set us on a path for long-term success. They're just interested in that hot, quick flash.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Like, you know, it's not smart.
Devin E: I'm worried.
Devin E: I was thinking… I was actually thinking about…
Devin E: the sphere, and just, like, see if there's, like, could there be different solutions? Because, you know, there's a pause on…
Devin E: Permits and just, like, All that now.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): What kind of permits is there a pause on?
Devin E: Well, like, they… till April 30th, that's why they're…
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Oh, you mean the moratorium on data centers?
Devin E: Yeah.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Yeah, there is currently a moratorium.
Devin E: And my question is, the report that they did, did you see the report that they generated from the task force? Yes. Did you read it? I did read it through.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Did you notice anything about that report?
Devin E: Monique.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): What was missing from that report?
Devin E: Yeah, to me, I was not underst… the money stuff, the permit, who is even owning the… That is…
Staci Hartwell (she/her): one issue? What were some other issues that sort of stood out to you on that report?
Devin E: they, to me, I did not see any experts on, or, like, majority experts on, like, environment, and, like.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): elves.
Devin E: Yeah, literally that type of stuff, like, they didn't…
Staci Hartwell (she/her): say, none.
Devin E: It was mostly… mostly, like, people that were… Pushing for the… Data centers in general.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): When we went to vote on this, I was… I was the only person that was… that was a dissenter on the vote.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Everybody else just said it was. And may I tell you something? What was also kind of bogus about that report? They included an entire attachment to that report that they gave to us the very day that they voted. We barely had enough people there to do a quorum, so people didn't even have a chance to see that report before they just unilaterally voted, yes, we want data centers. So you could have said that there was cancer
Staci Hartwell (she/her): In a data center, and put that on the first page in big, big red bold letters, they wouldn't have cared.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): They just wanted a data center because of the promise of all the money, and that is just really irresponsible legislating.
Devin E: I see. Do you think… is it… is it, like, a trend in PG County? Because I'm from Montgomery County, but I go to school in PT. Do you see that as, like, a trend of how they…
Devin E: Deal with money and then communities.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Well, I've not been around… I've not been back here long enough to determine just exactly how they manage the money, although I'm starting to hear stories about how they manage money, but…
Staci Hartwell (she/her): What I can say, and this is what the NAACP report, the discovery report shows, that there is a history, and there's a really good, thing I want you to re… to hear from a constituent in District 9, how they felt about it, and I'm gonna… Because that's a good… that's a good thing for you to be able to reference.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And here, you know, how community regards this. One second, let me put that in the thing for you to listen to also.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): I'm doing pretty good with all this linking and stuff.
Devin E: Yes. It's coming in clutch.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): There's one, and I want you to listen to what this man says, and you stay on to the end to hear about what… how constituents feel about it, and the legislators who put this stuff forward. They have a history, there is a pattern.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): of them doing this to this community. You know why? They don't value this community. You know what? You know what, I use it as, I use the analogy of a handsome or pretty person who dates.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): When you're pretty, and you're handsome, guess what? You're gonna hold people to a higher standard, because you're like, look, I'm worth it. You can't just come up here and just offer me hot dogs when I'm used to having steak. No, you gotta do something better, and if Prince George's County knew what it was worth, its value, they would not allow this to happen.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And that's… that's how we really have become, like, you know, the wasteland for the DMV.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): for… around the Capitol Beltway.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): All the bad stuff comes here first.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And we get it, and we get the bad stuff first, and we get the worst of the bad stuff over any other community.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And here's an Instagram post, you should look at those two posts, because it really sums up, really, how people are feeling.
Devin E: Right.
Devin E: Huh?
Devin E: Yeah, I would… I do want to get some more community.
Devin E: members' opinions.
Devin E: I'll probably, if I'm able to contact those people.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Oh, I don't think their names are in here.
Devin E: Okay, that's all fine. I think con- I mean, still help with the context as well.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): It really does.
Devin E: Yeah. Yeah, I definitely heard about that.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): What school are you in there? School of Journalism, or Politics?
Devin E: Saying.
Devin E: It's journalism.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Okay.
Devin E: Yes. So I'm in the… Right now, I'm in, like, this Bureau for Data Visualization.
Devin E: Yeah. I'm trying to think about the questions. I do… so… I heard that…
Devin E: You have some knowledge on, like, energy and environment, so…
Devin E: Could you give me some insight if, like…
Devin E: On exactly, like, hyperscale, large-scale data centers, and how it can impact energy.
Devin E: Maybe if that trip, like, goes into, like, bills and, like, bills.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Well, one thing I like to tell people is that the knee bone is connected to the thigh bone.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Whenever you get a hyperscale data center in a region, and we are in what they call the PJM,
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And that PJM manages utility for 13 states.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And whatever happens in any one of those 13 states affects the other 12.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): So when Virginia builds a data center.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Everybody within that PJM pays for that utility.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Now, this is a particularly large data center that they're proposing. What that means is that there's going to be a larger demand for electricity.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And the people who… who make our electricity.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And then the people who distribute the electricity have got to make money on that, because they answer to shareholders.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): They are… our utilities are run by people who are trying to make as much money profit as they can.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And Maryland guarantees them that profit for delivering this service to end users, to residents.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And it's gotten so bad because these, these, generation companies and these distribution companies like Exelon and Constellation, it's gotten so bad, they're so powerful, that most people don't buck them, don't, don't say, no, we can't do this, we can't afford it, until people started complaining about these data centers.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): So, that's really how the knee bone is connected to the thigh bone. You have these hyperscale data center, people are saying, we need lots and lots of electricity. You've got the utility companies, the distribution, and the generation companies saying, well, it is our obligation to provide that utility. And in order for us to do this, in order for us to do that, we've got to bill you now for utility that we will need to generate later.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): So that is how our utility bills are going up so much now.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): I mean, some of the testimonies are just incredible.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And one… this… the one that I sent you, the TikTok that I sent you, is one guy who tells you what their utility bill is. It's just insane, but that's the connection. Is that responsive to your question?
Devin E: Yeah, that is. Do you understand, like, the grids? Is that, like, the same thing?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): The grid, yeah, it is… the grid is… is… is… is compromised, and you know what a great website… did anyone tell you about the, Office of the People's Council website?
Devin E: No, I don't think so.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): You're so lucky you called me today.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Okay, so let me give you the Office of the People's Council, Maryland Data Center. Okay, Office of the People's Council, Data Center, but duh, Proposed Data Center Granicus, ba-ba.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): data centers. It's the thing, that's all… and it talks about the capacity markets, transmission, energy market, data center costs. I don't know, it might be information overload for you.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): But it is…
Devin E: I can see… I just want to see which one could be more compelling and, like.
Devin E: Like, what topic? Because there's so much, this is really, like…
Devin E: Layered type of thing, like the race, environment, health, and then, like.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): It is multi-layered. It is not a simple solution.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And what I, what I found, Office of the PEOPLE, People's Council, SEO,
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Yep, you check them out there about data centers.
Devin E: Okay, perfect.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And it talks about, you know, resource adequacy, or the lack thereof. And another thing that's really great is the Piedmont Reliability Project. It's very interesting. Yeah, it is a multi-layer, it is an onion.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): It is a multi-layered issue, but the thing is, is that we're going, headfirst into this, the proliferation data centers, without understanding what the consequences are!
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And every indication that they've received thus far says that, you know, there's every reason to say, stop.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): You know?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): So…
Devin E: Yeah, I'm definitely think… yeah, that's what I'm thinking, too, and it's like… I'm trying to…
Devin E: see, like, a comparison to Ashburn, because when I even look at the map, the map they provide for some sites, they include
Devin E: the Ashburn, Virginia site.
Devin E: in the thing. So I'm like.
Devin E: have they seen even a pattern? So that's why I'm trying to look into that, too.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Well, I think the EJ tools will give you that indication, like, hey, why is this all this stuff going into this demo… this geography?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): versus that geography, and the screening tools show you that. As a matter of fact, they had maps at one time that, you know, showed intensity of color, and the more intense colors were in the zip codes where Black and Brown folks live. And you could just say it was a great visual.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): To show you that, oh, it's concentrated around Baltimore City, Prince George's County, and Wacomico County on the eastern shore.
Devin E: Okay, so that, what's it called?
Devin E: the, like… The mapping thing screen you're talking about, was it just, like, environmental justice, like, in general?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Well, health and environment.
Devin E: Okay, health environment, okay.
Devin E: Yeah, I'll definitely look into that.
Devin E: I'm trying to think if I've had another question.
Devin E: Clarity on…
Staci Hartwell (she/her): You gotta watch those TikToks.
Devin E: I will. I'll watch you tomorrow.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Instagram, hmm?
Devin E: Yeah, I will. I mean, I'll see if I've seen it, too. Like, I was looking online.
Devin E: for, testimonies and, like, people talking. I'll definitely look into those.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Now, are you able to quote a source from, like, TikTok, and say, like, one resident said, but… and not have their name or anything?
Devin E: I'm not sure, like…
Devin E: I'll have to talk to my editor. I would probably just have to disclose, like, I didn't… I'm not the one who…
Devin E: When it asks them.
Devin E: I could…
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Well, this is public testimony.
Devin E: Yeah, okay, that's true, it's true.
Devin E: Okay, yeah, I mean, yeah, I'm gonna ask my… I'm sure I can include it.
Devin E: Because I do want this story also to feel a little bit more…
Devin E: multi-platform. That's why I'm including, like, the data viz, so it's like.
Devin E: If I can even, like, link the… TikTok.
Devin E: as well.
Devin E: Wait, yeah. Let's see if I… okay, because I want to understand, do you have…
Devin E: Any, like, insight on, like, the impacts? You talked about the power a bit, like, also water supply?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): I talked about what?
Devin E: You talked about the impacts on the power grid. Do you have…
Devin E: Insights on how it can impact the water supply.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): I attended a talk About this… there's this organization that is focused on water.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): On the Potomac River in particular.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And you know about the sewage spill.
Devin E: Yes, I do, yeah.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Yeah, so…
Staci Hartwell (she/her): They were talking about the availability of drinking water, water period. We are currently in a water deficit around the globe.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): We are consuming more water Then… and then our… our planet can produce.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Why would we want to, because Prince George's County is on a rolling, rationing… ration, for water.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): It's not critical, but every now and again, we have to dial down our consumption.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): So, why would they add A system that literally uses as much water as an entire city or town.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): per data center.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Now, they have 200 of them down in Virginia.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Why would they propose a proliferation for them here in Maryland? It just… it just doesn't… you know, like, they say, make it make sense.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): So, you are, you're looking at a system that uses, what, 100,000 gallons?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Of water per day?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): How does that make… I…
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And you're in a water deficit, and the water that you currently have right now is so polluted, but the, you know, the data center really… the hyperscale center wouldn't come for another 5 years, so they will probably have the sewage thing figured out by then, but…
Devin E: Yeah.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): It just, like I said, it just doesn't make sense.
Devin E: Yeah, I was… I'm gonna look into, like, the… Numbers… And compare, like.
Devin E: how much exactly gallons. But yeah, I know it's crazy. I mean, that's, like, one of the biggest talking points of the data centers, just, like, how much water it consumes just to cool down.
Devin E: systems, and then having large-scale ones would just be ridiculous. Like, me looking at the Contero Drive, the potential site, that… the amount of acres that I measured was ridiculous.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Yeah.
Devin E: Trade?
Devin E: Like, I'm playing?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And the hyperscale, the one up in Frederick, Maryland, is 2,200 acres.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): It's huge!
Devin E: That's insane.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And you know what, see, they're comparing apples to apples. See, in Virginia, you have less people, more land.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): In Prince George's County, you have more people and less land.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): So how does that make sense? You can't compare the two.
Devin E: Right.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And you know, let me tell you the other thing about water. It's not just the consumption of the water, it's the discharge.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): What are you gonna do with all that polluted water?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Gonna put it back in the river?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): in the wa… in the ocean, I'm… I mean…
Staci Hartwell (she/her): You know, where are you gonna put all that water?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): You can't put it back into where it came from, because now it's polluted.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): So not only are you taking a lot of water, but what do you do with it once you used it?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): It's certainly not potable after that.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): So…
Staci Hartwell (she/her): The issue with water is not the amount of consumption, and then the discharge of all that polluted water.
Devin E: Okay.
Devin E: I'm gonna note that… I…
Devin E: you did, like, touch on, like, how Virginia is getting less… like, the population density is less compared to PG, and I was trying to get a map of that as well, but…
Devin E: And that kind of relates to this conversation.
Devin E: About if they should be placed in, like.
Devin E: more industrial areas compared to residential areas. I want to see people's takes on that conversation. What would yours be?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Well, it's the obvious, why would you put them where people live?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): With children, you know, people live, work, and play.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): I mean, that's putting people in harm's way.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And when you know better, why would you do that? I don't know, I think it's grounds for a lot of lawsuits, too.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Because if you know all this stuff up front, and you still, you still allow this to happen, it seems like, to me, someone needs to be accountable when, you know, COPD… you know… Pristers County receives an F.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): has consistently received a failing grade, oftentimes F, from the American Lung Association for Air Quality.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Why would you add, a,
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Project that has, you know, massive amounts of diesel emissions.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): From their backup generators.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Why would you put that next door to… I mean, I was… I was over there the other day, a friend of mine lives over there where the data center is. It is literally across… have you… have you been there?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): To the side?
Devin E: The Landover?
Devin E: Yeah.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Across the street is where people live. Right behind there are big, huge communities of single-family homes. So you got the data center to the south of these homes, you have the highway to the east of these homes. I mean, those people are sitting in the bullseye of some of the greatest carbon emissions in the state.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Why would you do that? It…
Staci Hartwell (she/her): I… and then these elected people are supposed to be there to represent our best interest.
Devin E: So why are they motivated to do something that's so harmful to communities?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): No, no, no.
Devin E: Nearing money, like, there's just, like, But it's like…
Staci Hartwell (she/her): It's bad money.
Devin E: Gosh, yeah.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): It's literally dirty money.
Devin E: Yeah.
Devin E: I've been trying to get in contact with, like, council members.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Oh, they ain't not gonna talk to you.
Devin E: Okay.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): They don't want to be held accountable, and you should try.
Devin E: Yeah, I'mma try.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Because it's all… I always love it when you say that, you know, this reporter attempted to reach every council people, and they all refused to speak to me.
Devin E: Hmm.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): I think that's always… I think that's always meaningful.
Devin E: Yeah, I'm gonna try,
Devin E: I'll just get their numbers and call. Maybe I'll, like, frame it in a different way. I just want to know their… like, it's not even to accuse, like, it's really just to know the perspective, like…
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Then they're gonna… they're gonna give you a pet answer.
Devin E: I mean, I think that's… that's good, too, because I can… the way with this… I mean, the data's gonna show, and then the people are gonna show.
Devin E: The story, you know, so that would… Yep.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And then how is it, this is a question I have, too, how is it that you can have 23,000 plus people on a petition, then you have hordes of people showing up to give testimony about why these things are bad? How is it the people that you elected are voting against the will of the people?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): How does that happen?
Devin E: Yeah, that's… Has there been any votes, like, lately? Like, there hasn't been any…
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Well, there's an election coming up.
Devin E: Yeah, that's the only thing.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And that's a good place for us to really vote our concerns.
Devin E: Yeah.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Because I don't think that they deserve our trust.
Devin E: I've been thinking that. I'm also, like, read, like, this bill, I don't know if it passed yet, because I was trying to see the bill that.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): County or state?
Devin E: Let me find it, pull my notes.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): because there are several, data center bills at the state level that are being proposed, and you know, we are in active legislative session now. Several bills.
Devin E: the Senate one, the three.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Okay, so the Congress. The U.S. Congress bill by Chris Van Hollen?
Devin E: Yeah, the 397 one?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): What's the name of it?
Devin E: let's say, Senate Bill 397.
Devin E: About the tax exemptions?
Devin E: for the sale of qualified data centers, like, proble… personal property.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Why would they be exempt from taxes?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): That is… they're supposed to generate income, and now we're…
Staci Hartwell (she/her): There's a great article that was done on the study in Virginia about how they're losing money, because they gave all these incentives to data centers, and now they're losing money.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): That's what I'm saying, you get that big flash of cash up front, but you give them so many incentives, it takes it all away. No one's looking at this in a 360, you know? No one is, and it's just… it's just really bad management.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Yeah. It's disappointing.
Devin E: That's, like, when I was gonna talk to council members, like, there's some that are not… they're not super pushing for the data centers, but it's like, you know, you're still… have to hold your combo. I was gonna ask them more about the money aspect.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): There was only one councilperson at our… at the last community meeting I attended, it's been about a month or so. There was only one person, Chris Oriata, that stood up and said that she does not see the wisdom in advancing data centers. Everyone else says, well, you know, it's gonna bring a lot of money.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): It's… we're gonna have a lot of money! And it's like, she was the only person
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And all the rest of the people are voting against… all the rest of the council people were voting against the interests of their people.
Devin E: Sorry.
Devin E: Yeah.
Devin E: I'm definitely gonna look that up, cause I'm just gonna…
Devin E: I think a way to… for me to get some more information from them is just to ask more about the money aspect.
Devin E: Like, the revenue, so that's definitely one due.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Yeah, and you know, you have to ask them questions that lead them into the dead end that they're… the corner they're painting themselves into. Saying, you know, you've talked about, you know, for example, you've talked about all the money that is generated from data centers. What about… how does that… how does that compare to the incentives that the state gives them?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): You know, on… for tax breaks.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): And has anyone really meted out, measured out.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): What the impact of all the benefits are, of what they perceive the benefits to be, to what the actual costs are relative to health, the environment, you know, property values, etc.
Devin E: True.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Yeah, because they haven't done it.
Devin E: Yeah, like, the report didn't really even talk about that type of stuff, so it's like…
Staci Hartwell (she/her): bitten.
Devin E: No.
Devin E: Hmm. Okay.
Devin E: Yeah, hopefully I get in contact. I do… like, one of my…
Devin E: One of the people in my class, like, she has personal numbers of, because she reported…
Devin E: PG before, so I'll definitely, if I have to, I'll just reach out to her.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): What's your timing on your article?
Devin E: I'm trying… see, there's not… I do want to get it before…
Devin E: like, the middle of April, probably, like, the end of March, because after that… and it's, like, basically, I'm just trying to get more productive, and the maps are done, because…
Devin E: After the April 30th, when the withholding is lifted, I kinda… I want people to…
Devin E: Have this article out before that time.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Okay, well, alright, make it happen, Devin!
Devin E: Yes, alright. Well, yeah, I don't have any more questions. Is there anything I didn't talk about that you would at least want in the story, or, like, think would be helpful?
Staci Hartwell (she/her): there's so much I could pull out of the air for you.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): But…
Staci Hartwell (she/her): I'd be happy if you want… if you want to share with me your outline to look at and see where there's some gaps might be.
Devin E: Okay, yeah, that would be helpful. So I could contact you, like, if… Sure. I'm working? Okay, yeah.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): Oh god, yeah, just send me an email.
Devin E: Alright.
Devin E: That would be good. Do you help me so much, especially with that screen mapping?
Devin E: Yeah. Because, I mean, that's essentially what I was doing, too, but I was doing more, like, where the data centers are, so this would be so helpful.
Staci Hartwell (she/her): I think it's a good tool.
Devin E: Yeah.
Devin E: Okay, but that is all. I'm gonna stop recording.